<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dibyendu Tapadar</title>
    <link>https://dibyendupm.netlify.app/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dibyendu Tapadar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://dibyendupm.netlify.app/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AssessEd - Bridging gap between the digital EdTech world and Offline Assessments.</title>
      <link>https://dibyendupm.netlify.app/blog/byjus-assessed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dibyendupm.netlify.app/blog/byjus-assessed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An AI-powered digital platform designed for edTech organizations, enabling the digital capture of pen-and-paper test transcripts and scores. This facilitates the enhancement of student learning outcomes by allowing for the personalization of educational offerings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;ree&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f3d706_a2c9e1602581406a8b5f4beebc0ee438~mv2.png/v1/fill/w_1199,h_749,al_c,q_90,enc_avif,quality_auto/f3d706_a2c9e1602581406a8b5f4beebc0ee438~mv2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Role&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- 2021, Product Manager, Byjus -&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked with our multidisciplinary team to take AssessEd from implementation to growth, maturity and retirement (replacing with an enhaced platform). I conducted research, user interviews, managed onboarding, oversaw AI training, and worked closely with the CEO, product designer and engineering managers to enhance, mature and integrate the system with multiple existing systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DearO - the simplest and smartest Automobile Workshop Management system</title>
      <link>https://dibyendupm.netlify.app/blog/dearo-wms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dibyendupm.netlify.app/blog/dearo-wms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;origin-story&#34;&gt;Origin Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, despite holding over 50% of the market share, the unauthorized car repair workshops relied on manual pen and paper processes. They failed to follow the digital trend, missing out on benefits that the taxis and food delivery industry was gaining. As a consequence, they were unable to provide their customers with an improved and transparent experience, and they also failed to optimize their daily operations by harnessing the power of technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khan Academy for Tutors</title>
      <link>https://dibyendupm.netlify.app/blog/khan-for-tutors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dibyendupm.netlify.app/blog/khan-for-tutors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;ree&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f3d706_352ca2ef376a446f9a84a7d197387b11~mv2.png/v1/fill/w_1216,h_554,al_c,q_90,enc_avif,quality_auto/f3d706_352ca2ef376a446f9a84a7d197387b11~mv2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-product&#34;&gt;The Product&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Khan for Educators is a powerful tool built on top of Khan Academy&amp;rsquo;s world-renowned educational content, designed specifically for teachers. Khan for Educators revolutionizes the teaching and learning experience by providing a comprehensive set of tools for tutors to create classes, add students, assign videos and assessments, and track individual progress and mastery levels at a concept level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-features&#34;&gt;Core Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Class Creation: Teachers can effortlessly create classes, organizing students and content in a streamlined manner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Education with Automated Assessment - A Journey in Innovation in Byjus</title>
      <link>https://dibyendupm.netlify.app/blog/automated-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dibyendupm.netlify.app/blog/automated-assessments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the ever-evolving landscape of education, the integration of technology has become paramount. My journey as a product manager at Byju&amp;rsquo;s, a leading ed-tech company, reflects this transformation. I led the development of an automation tool that revolutionized the traditional methods of test creation and assessment, aligning perfectly with the modern educational needs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;ree&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f3d706_48f46023467c490fa5aa7e25517a838d~mv2.png/v1/fill/w_1480,h_846,al_c,q_90,usm_0.66_1.00_0.01,enc_avif,quality_auto/f3d706_48f46023467c490fa5aa7e25517a838d~mv2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;My Role:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a product manager, my role was multifaceted. I was not only the brainchild behind this initiative but also the driving force in its execution. My responsibility encompassed everything from conceptualization to overseeing the development and implementation of the tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
